字幕翻译: 乔葱葱
1995年, 一个叫安迪的男孩在生日时得到了一个巴斯光年玩具
In 1995, a boy named Andy got a Buzz Lightyear toy for his birthday.
这个玩具来自于他最喜欢的电影
It was from his favorite movie.
就是这部电影
This is that movie.
未知空间 距地球420万光年
UNCHARTED SPACE 4.2 MILLION LIGHT YEARS FROM EARTH
星际指挥部SC-01探索船 船员1200人
STAR COMMAND SC-01 EXPLORATION VESSEL CREW: 1200
巴斯光年任务日志 星际日期3901年
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 3901.
传感器在一个未知星球上
Sensors have detected potential life forms.
检测到可能有生命存在
on an uncharted planet.
所以我们要绕道去调查一下
So, we're making a detour to investigate.
太空游侠会进行初步评估
Space Rangers will make initial evaluation,
然后决定是否唤醒冬眠中的
then assess whether it's worth waking the science crew
科学船员
from their hyper-sleep.
当ERIC采集核心样本时
While the ERIC takes core samples
我将探索一下这个陌生星球有没有什么奇怪地方
I will explore further the oddities of this strange planet.
地面看来有点不太稳定
Terrain seems a bit unstable.
还没有检测到此区域是否可以进行呼吸
No read-out yet if the area is breathable.
似乎没有任何智慧生命存在的迹象
There seems to be no sign of intelligent life anywhere.
-你在和谁说话？-没和谁
-Who are you talking to? -No one.
你又在自言自语
You were narrating again.
才不是呢 我在做任务日志呢
I was not. Just doing the mission log.
不会有人听你的日志的
You do know no one ever listens to them.
我知道 只不过这样能让我集中注意力
I know that, narrating helps me with focus.
-保持头脑敏锐 -好吧
-Stay sharp. -Yeah.
好吧 霍桑指挥官 如果你介意这个
Well, if it bothers you, Commander Hawthorne.
我很乐意回萝卜号上等着
I'm happy to wait back on the turnip.
请别叫它萝卜号
Please don't call it the turnip.
但这艘船看起就像个萝卜
But the ship looks like a root vegetable.
好啦 你在设计图预览时都说过了
Yes, you made that very clear at the design review.
你知道我自言自语有多久了?
How long have you known that I narrate?
从我们都还是学员的时候就一直这样
Forever. Since you and I were cadets.
说到这 你忘了带那个菜鸟来了
Speaking of, you forgot to take the rookie with you.
啊 霍桑指挥官 你知道我对菜鸟是什么感觉
Ah, Commander Hawthorne, you know how I feel about rookies.
这和我对自动驾驶的感觉一样
It's the same way I feel about autopilots.
"先生 有什么可以协助你的吗？有什么我可以做的吗？"
"How may I assist you? Is there anything I can do, sir?"
他们帮不上忙 却能把简单的事情复杂化
They don't help, they just over-complicate things.
所以我最好还是自己亲手来
I'm better off just doing the job myself.
所以我把菜鸟带来了
Which is why I brought the rookie.
你好
Hello.
-不是吧 -巴斯 规定要求我们把他带上
-No. -Buzz, protocol requires we bring him along.
-他的眼神会充满悲伤 -巴斯
-He's gonna have sad eyes. -Buzz.
你知道我受不了这种眼神
You know I can't deal with sad eyes.
-看看这个菜鸟 巴斯 -不
-Look at the rookie, Buzz. -No.
-看看这个菜... 看... -不... ...不
-Look at the roo...Look... -No...no.
-光年 -不
-Lightyear. -No.
-看看他 -不看
-Look at him. -Not looking.
-看 看 -不
-Look. Look. -No.
-看看这个菜鸟 -不 不
-Look at the rookie. -No. No.
好的 好吧 好吧 你赢了
All right. All right. You win.
瞧啊 费瑟... 费瑟汉姆斯坦...
Look, Feather...Featheringhamstan...
是费瑟林汉姆斯坦长官
It's Featheringhamstan, sir.
听着 菜鸟 首先 没人跟你说话你就闭嘴
Look, rookie, first, you will not speak unless spoken to.
-是的 长官 -我还没说完呢
-Yes, sir. -Still talking.
第二 尊重制服
Second, respect the suit.
这制服意味着什么
This suit means something.
它不仅仅是在保护你的身体 更是在保护整个宇宙
It's not just protecting your body, it's protecting the universe.
这制服是你对世界的承诺
This suit is a promise to the world that you,
最重要的事情是
and you alone will do one thing above all.
不惜一切代价完成任务
Finnish the mission no matter the cost.
你永远不能放弃 不管你在星际中遇见什么状况... ...
You will never quit, whatever the galaxy may throw your way--
关掉那个玩意！
Will you please turn that off!
这也太简单了
It's just too easy.
你在讽刺我 是吗？
You're mocking me, aren't you?
是的 但这是支持你的一种方式
Yeah, but in a supportive way.
听着 我想说的是 指挥官 我们俩已经把这项工作搞定了
Look, what I'm trying to say, Commander, is that you and I have this job down.
-长官 -我还没说完
-Sir. -Still talking.
在任何时候我都知道你在想什么 我知道你会去哪里
At any moment I know what you're thinking, I know where you're gonna be.
但这个人 我不知道
But this guy, I don't know.
他去哪了？
Where'd he go?
你看到了吗？这正是我要说的
You see? This is exactly what I'm talking about.
他不是在帮忙 人都没影了
He's not helping. He's wandered off.
是藤条！
Vines!
有虫子！
Bugs!
飞船正在往下陷
The ship. It's sinking.
各位 回到萝卜号上！
Everyone, back to the turnip!
哦 现在可以叫萝卜了
Oh, so now it's the turnip.
启动隐身模式 这应该为我们争取到足够的时间
Engage Stealth Mode. That should buy us enough time.
我们到不了了
We're not gonna make it.
就快到了！
Almost there!
好吧 执行B计划 准备好了吗？
Okay, plan B. Ready?
开始吧！
Go!
-该死！-我可以把它接好
-Blast! -Here, I can re-route it.
给我点时间
Just give me a minute.
那谁去哪儿了...
Where is the...
救命啊！
Help!
菜鸟
rookie.
救救我！
Help me!
巴斯光年任务日志 这个星球完全不适合居住
Buzz Lightyear mission log. The planet is clearly uninhabitable.
事实上 全是敌对生物
In fact, outright hostile.
会动的植物抓住了学员弗斯-费瑟林...
The sentient foliage have apprehended cadet Furth-Feathering...
费瑟林斯顿...费瑟...费瑟...
Featheringston...Feather...
他们抓走了菜鸟
They got the rookie,
那个我一开始就强烈反对他加入的...
who I strongly suggested should not have joined in the first--
该死的
Blast.
-巴斯！-现在！
-Buzz! -Now!
快走吧 游侠！
Move it, ranger!
我们正在返回船上的路上
Making our way back to the ship.
快点 巴斯！
Come on, Buzz!
快点！
Hurry!
引擎室一切正常
All good at the engine room.
-我去开飞船 -那我--
-I'll take the helm. -And I will--
什么都别做 我来就行
Do nothing. I've got this.
有什么需要我协助的吗？
How may I assist you?
自动导航仪
Autopilots.
-有什么我可以做的吗 先生？-没有 什么也没有！
-Is there anything I can do, sir? -No and no!
这可不是在玩模拟器
This is not a simulation.
指挥官 报告状态！
Commander, status!
燃油注入
Fuel engaged.
所有系统运行
All systems go.
警告 发射轨迹不正常
Warning. Launch trajectory unsound.
起来吧 起来吧
Come on. Come on.
即将发生碰撞
Collision imminent.
中止 中止
Abort. Abort.
光年船长 需要我帮忙吗？
Captain Lightyear, do you need my help?
-不需要 -你确定吗？
-Negative. -Are you sure?
我是巴斯光年 我总是很确定
I'm Buzz Lightyear. I'm always sure.
糟透了 巴斯
It's bad, Buzz.
光速驱动晶体完全损坏了
The hyper-speed crystal was totally destroyed.
长话短说 我们被困在这了
Long story short: we're marooned.
我不知道
I don't know.
你这是干什么?
What are you doing?
送自己上军事法庭
I'm court-martialing myself.
别 别这样
No. You're not.
霍桑指挥官 我特此解除自己太空游侠的职务
Commander Hawthorne, I hereby relieve myself of all Space Ranger duties.
这是我的错 这些人原本应该好好的
This was my fault. And these people deserve better.
你可以把我关起来
You can throw me in the brig.
完成任务 巴斯
Finish the mission, Buzz.
这就是我们应该做的
That's what we do.
但得等到所有人都回家了才算完成任务
We're not done until everyone gets home.
但我们没有燃料晶体
But we have no fuel crystal.
所以我们在这个星球上开采资源 制造一个新晶体
So we mine resources on this planet, create a new crystal.
晶体融合是非常不稳定的
Crystalic fusion is highly unstable.
那我们测试它
Then we test it.
不 这太危险了
No. It's too dangerous.
制造一块光速驱动晶体
Manufacturing a crystal capable of hyper-speed
就像试图把太阳套住
is like trying to lasso with the sun.
然后需要有人把太阳装到飞船上
And then someone would need to attach that sun to a ship,
然后需要有人来驾驶这艘船而不把自己炸成碎片
and then the ship needs someone to fly it without blowing themselves into oblivion.
谁会动这种念头...
Who in their right mind would...
巴斯光年任务日志 星际日期3902年
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 3902.
在被困住一整年之后
After a full year of being marooned,
我们的专业人员
our specialized crew
已经给这个星球的资源开发了不可思议的用途
have put this planet's vast resources to incredible use.
终于 我们将进行第一次光速试飞
Finally, our first hyper-speed test flight is a go.
准备好了吗 光年船长？
Ready, Captain Lightyear?
我准备好了 霍桑指挥官
Ready as I'll ever be, Commander Hawthorne.
飞向宇宙
To infinity.
浩瀚无垠
And beyond.
-嗡！-我们在外围有一个漏洞
-Buzz! -We got a breach in the perimeter.
拜托 我就...
Come on, I just...
光年船长！
Captain Lightyear!
艾尔曼·迪亚兹
Airman Diaz.
孩子们 今天藤条有那么点活跃 是吧？
Boy, the vines are a little feisty today, huh?
我们准备好发射了吗?
Are we ready to launch?
如果你准备好了 我们都准备好了 先生
We're all ready if you are, sir.
一年的工作只为了四分钟的飞行 这值得庆祝吗？
A year of work for a four minute flight. Isn't that something?
当然值得
Sure is.
好吧 我们去瞧瞧新的光速驱动燃料是否稳定
Well, let's go find out if this new hyper-speed fuel is stable.
这样我就可以让我们离开这块石头了
So I can get us off this rock.
差点忘了 这是你的I. V. A. N 先生
I almost forgot. Here's your I.V.A.N, sir.
充满电了
Fully loaded.
自动导航仪
Autopilots.
这儿 这是XL-01
And here, of course, is the XL-01.
完美的座驾
Pretty sweet ride.
现在拿上你的燃料晶体
Now let's get you that fuel crystal.
早上好 光年船长
Good morning, Captain Lightyear.
这是为你特别配制的混合燃料
Here is your specially formulated fuel mixture.
那么 这燃料能驱动到光速？
So, this is the fuel that's gonna reach hyper-speed?
有87.6%的机会
It has an 87.6 percent chance.
我接受这个概率
I'll take those odds.
祝你好运 船长
Good luck, Captain.
我们都指望着你...
We're all counting on you...
艾尔曼
Airman.
XL-01呼叫任务控制中心 你收到了吗？
XL-01 to Mission Control. Do you copy?
收到 XL-01
Copy, XL-01.
我准许你离开星球四分钟
I'm gonna grant you four minutes to be off planet,
但你可得回来
but then you come right back to us.
这可是命令
That's an order.
收到
Roger that.
我就冲着光速来了
Hyper Speed, here I come.
倒数10...
T minus 10...
...9...
...nine...
...8 7...
...eight, seven...
...6...
...six...
...5 4...
...five, four...
...3 2...
...three, two...
...1 发射
...one. Launch.
I. V. A. N. 调出飞行计划
I.V.A.N., pull up the flight plan, please.
你好 我是你的内部 --
Hello. I am your internal--
自动导航仪
Autopilots.
你好 我是你的内置声控导航仪 请叫我I.V.A.N
Hello, I am your internal voice-activated navigator, call me I.V.A.N.
请准备好飞行计划 I.V.A.N
Ready the flight plan, please, I.V.A.N.
当然可以
Certainly.
你的任务是加速穿越深空
Your mission is to accelerate through deep space,
绕过特卡尼阿尔法星
slingshot around Alpha T'Kani,
然后通过减速环回到塔卡尼主星
then through the deceleration rings back here to T'kani Prime.
目标飞行时间： 4分28秒
Target flight time: 4 minutes, 28 seconds.
XL-01 你可以启动光速飞行了
XL-01, you are clear for hyper-launch.
收到 控制中心 启动光速飞行
Copy, control. Initiating hyper-launch.
接近50%光速
Approaching 50 percent hyper speed.
燃料稳定
Fuel stable.
将速度提高到0.6c
Increasing speed to 0.6c.
60%光速
Sixty percent hyper-speed.
增加速度至0.7c
Increasing speed to 0.7c.
70%光速
Seventy percent hyper-speed.
燃料稳定
Fuel stable.
接近0.8c
Approaching 0.8c.
推进到光速
Pushing to hyper-speed.
一号发动机失效
Failure in Engine 1.
燃料单元失稳
Fuel cell unstable.
I.V.A.N. 报告状态：
I.V.A.N., status.
轨迹错误 偏移四度
Trajectory error, plus four degrees.
如果不纠正航向将错过减速环
Failure to course-correct will result in missing the rings.
我们会飞向深空
We'll fly off into deep space
那必死无疑
resulting in certain death.
是的 谢谢你
Yes, thank you.
弹射是你唯一选项
Ejection is your only option.
不 不 我能做到
No, no. I can do it.
警告 你有26秒的时间来纠正航线
Warning. You have 26 seconds to course-correct.
你现在有25秒的时间来纠正航向
You now have 25 seconds to course-correct.
-你现在有... -请停止倒数
-You now have-- -Stop counting, please.
我很抱歉 我的安全规定禁止我停止倒数
I'm sorry. My safety protocols prohibit me from terminating countdown.
自动导航仪
Autopilots.
任务即将失败 请记录你的遗言
Mission failure imminent. Please record your last words.
不会是今天的 I.V.A.N.
Not today, I.V.A.N.
如果你对这个录音感到满意 请说话或选择1
If you are satisfied with this recording, speak or select 1.
I.V.A.N. 把引擎加到最大功率
I.V.A.N., push the engines all the way. Maximum power.
这样不行 燃料电池会爆炸...
That action is inadvisable. Fuel cell detonation--
我就想它爆炸呢
Is exactly what I'm counting on.
情况危急
Situation critical.
燃料电池接近峰值容量
Fuel cell approaching peak capacity.
打开燃料舱门 I. V. A. N.
Open up the Fuel Door, I.V.A.N.
很抱歉 我没听清
I'm sorry. I didn't quite catch that.
-请重述你的命令 -打开燃料舱门！
-Please restate your command. -Open fuel door!
五分钟后引爆...
Detonation in five...
...四...
...four...
...三...
...three...
...二...
...two...
-... ...一 -现在！
-...one. -Now!
航线已纠正
Course corrected.
你没能到达光速
You failed to reach hyper-speed.
我不需要听这个 I. V. A. N.
I didn't need to hear that, I.V.A.N.
你没听到？
You didn't hear that?
哦 很抱歉 我再重复一遍
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll repeat.
-不 我听到了...我是说... -你没能到达光速
-No, I've heard-- I meant-- -You failed to reach hyper-speed.
-谢谢你 I. V. A. N. -你没达到...
-Thank you, I.V.A.N. -You failed to reach--
指挥官 你还好吗？
Commander, are you okay?
迪亚兹 你长胡子了
Diaz, you grew a beard.
你是怎么长出胡子的？
How did you grow a beard?
哦 对了
Oh, right.
首先 欢迎回来
First of, welcome back.
其次...
Secondly...
等等
Wait.
等等 这是什么？
Wait, what is this?
我离开了多长时间？
How long was I gone?
4年2个月零3天
Four years, two months and three days.
什么？
What?
我还以为我们失去你了 巴斯
I thought we've lost you, Buzz.
艾莉莎 发生了什么事？
Alisha, what happened?
-时间膨胀 -什么？
-Time dilation. -What?
时间膨胀很简单
Time dilation is quite simple.
当你接近光速时 你的时间相对于我们的时间就变慢了
As you approached hyper-speed, your time slowed relative to our own.
所以 在你的任务中 你只过了几分钟
So, during your mission you aged only minutes,
而我们其他人却老了很多年
while the rest of us have aged years.
简单地说：你飞得越快...
Simply put: The faster you fly--
我飞得越快 就越能穿越到未来
The faster I fly the further into the future I travel.
我明白了
I get it.
那么 我们现在要做什么呢？
So, what are we gonna do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我认为我们应该暂停测试飞行
But I think we should hold off on any more test flights
直到我们想出别的办法
until we've figured out something else.
指挥官 我们说过要完成任务
Commander, we said finish the mission.
这就是太空游侠的工作
That's what Space Rangers do.
以什么为代价呢 巴斯？
At what cost, Buzz?
你愿意再损失四年时间吗？
Are you willing to lose another four years?
所以 大家被困在这里
So, everyone is just stuck here
全是因为我
because of me.
嘿 你没事吧？
Hey, you all right?
是的 是的 我很好
Yeah. Yeah. I'm fine.
等等 那是什么？
Wait, what's that?
哦 我订婚了
Oh, I got engaged.
哦 哇 那真是太好了 她叫什么名字？
Oh, wow. That's great. What's her name?
Kiko 她是科学小组的成员之一
Kiko. She's one of the science crew.
有趣的是 如果我们没被困住 这根本就不会发生
It's funny, it never would've mattered if we hadn't been stranded.
你和你刚认识的人订婚了？
You got engaged to someone you just met?
巴斯 我三年前就认识她了
Buzz, I met her three years ago.
哦 对 对
Oh, right. Right.
好吧 恭喜你 我很想见见她
Well, Congratulations. I'd love to meet her.
嗯 有的是时间 休息一下吧
Well, there's plenty of time for that. Get some rest.
这是命令
That's an order.
别客气！艾莉莎
YOU'RE WELCOME! ALISHA
你好 巴斯！
Hello, Buzz!
我是索克斯 你的私人机器人伴侣
I am Sox. Your personal companion robot.
我的什么？
My what?
我是星际指挥部派来的
I was issued by star command
来缓解你失去时间后的情绪变化
to ease your emotional transition after your time away.
哦 你考虑得可真周到 机器猫
Oh, that's very considerate of you, robot feline.
不过不用了 谢谢你
But no thank you.
恐怕这是规定
I'm afraid it's protocol.
传感器显示你已经错过了四个生日
Sensors indicate you've missed four birthdays.
你想来一套糖霜零食庆祝个生日吗？
Would you like a frosted snack kit to celebrate?
不用了 那会影响到我的营养控制
Negative. That would compromise my nutritional regiment.
我们可以谈谈你的感受 我是一个出色的倾听者
We can talk about your feelings. I am an excellent listener.
不 不 听着 我有非常漫长的... ... 一天？
No, no. Look, I've had a very long... day?
它没有按计划发展
It did not go as planned.
任务没成功？
The mission was unsuccessful?
是的
Affirmative.
哦 不 我很抱歉听到这个消息
Oh, no. I am so sorry to hear that.
谢谢你 索克斯
Thank you, Sox.
不客气 巴斯
You're welcome, Buzz.
我们玩游戏好吗？
Shall we play a game?
-不 谢谢你 -你确定吗？
-No, thank you. -Are you sure?
我可以根据你的性格特征 专门为你定制一个游戏
I can create a game specifically for you, based on your exact personality profile.
嘿 听着 索克斯 伙计 我很累了
Hey, listen, Sox, buddy, I'm pretty tired.
所以 我要去睡觉了
So, I'm gonna go ahead and hit the rack.
当然了
Of course.
如果你愿意 我可以提供助眠音
I can provide sleep sounds if you like.
有几个选项
I have several options.
夏天的夜晚 海洋的天堂 鲸鱼的叫声
Summer night, ocean paradise, whale calls.
不 不 白噪音就可以了
No, no. White noise is fine.
很好
Very well.
-晚安 索克斯 -晚安 巴斯
-Good night, Sox. -Good night, Buzz.
拉起来
Pull up.
光年船长 你需要帮助吗？
Captain Lightyear, do you need help?
不 我可以的
No. I can do it.
巴斯 你确定吗？
Buzz, are you sure?
恐怕这是规定
I'm afraid it's protocol.
我可以的！
I can do it!
我能做到的
I can do it.
传感器显示你做了个噩梦
Sensors indicate you had a nightmare.
-你想谈谈它吗？-不愿意
-Would you like to talk about it? -Negative.
好吧 但记住 我的任务是帮你
Okay, but remember, my mission is to help you.
而且我不会放弃我的任务
And I'm not giving up on my mission.
是吗？
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
你知道吗 索克斯 我也不会放弃我的任务
You know what, Sox, I'm not giving up on my mission either.
太好了!那我能做什么?
Great! So what can I do?
好吧 你为什么不和你的老鼠伙伴去玩
Well, why won't you engage with your mouse buddy.
还有什么更有挑战的吗？
Is there anything more challenging?
你想要挑战？好吧
You want a challenge? Okay.
我想你可以研究一下这个燃料稳定性的问题
I guess you could work on this fuel stability thing.
晶体融合 当然可以
Crystalic fusion. Of course.
你什么时候回来？
When should I expect you back?
大约4年后
About four years.
等一下 你没必要这么做
Hold on. You don't have to do this.
指挥官 这是我的错误
Commander, this is my mistake.
我需要把它纠正过来
I need to make it right.
好吧 但也许我们应该考虑一下
Okay, but maybe we should think about this.
考虑什么？拜托 我们是太空游侠
Think about what? Come on, we're Space Rangers.
我们就是要完成任务
We finish the mission.
好吧 能再次穿上这身制服很好
Well, it would be nice to wear the suit again.
人们开始忘记太空游侠的重要性
People are starting to forget Space Rangers ever mattered.
好吧 我正是要解决这个问题
Well, I'm about to fix that.
飞向宇宙
To infinity.
浩瀚无垠
And beyond.
不稳定
UNSTABLE
40周年快乐
HAPPY 40TH ANNIVERSARY
不稳定
UNSTABLE
嗨 巴斯
Hi, Buzz.
你会在一两年内回到这里...
You're back here in a year or two...
但是 我不会了
and, well, I won't.
我不知道什么时候发生的
I don't know when it happened
但我似乎已经变得很老了
but I seem to have gone and gotten very old.
我一直以为我们会再次成为太空游侠
I always thought we'd get to be Space Rangers again.
我怀念在穿梭在星空中的日子
I miss being out among the stars.
所有的冒险
All the adventures.
但相比这些 我更想念的是
But more than any of that
我想念你
I missed you.
嗨 奶奶
Hi, Grandma.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
我给我的朋友巴斯留个口信
I'm leaving a message for my friend, Buzz.
是太空游侠?
The Space Ranger?
是啊
That's right.
他现在还在太空中
He's in space right now.
哇
Wow.
这是我的孙女 依奇
This is my granddaughter, Izzy.
我也要成为一名太空游侠
I'm gonna be a Space Ranger too.
就像他一样?
Just like him?
就像你一样
Just like you.
再见 巴斯
Goodbye, Buzz.
很抱歉无法看着你完成任务了
I'm sorry I won't be there to see you finish the mission.
飞向宇宙
To infinity.
浩瀚无垠
And beyond.
咚咚 对不起 打扰了 我刚刚搬进我的新...
Knock. Knock. Sorry to interrupt. I'm just moving into my new-
看那！巴斯光年本人亲临了
Look at that! The actual Buzz Lightyear in the flesh.
是啊
Affirmative.
指挥官卡尔·伯恩赛德
Commander Cal Burnside.
我小的时候可是你的忠实粉丝
I was a big fan of your when I was a kid.
好吧 期待着与的你合作 最终能带我们离开这里
Well, then I look forward to working with you to finally get us out of here.
没有人告诉你吗？
Did no one tell you?
告诉我什么？
Tell me what?
好吧
Yeah.
那是最后一次任务了 巴斯
That was the last mission, Buzz.
你说什么？
What?
我们决定要继续留在这里
We've decided we gonna go ahead and stay right here.
等等 这里？不行 这不是一个可行的选择
Wait, here? Negative, that is not a viable option.
现在它是了 看 我们正在建造这个
It is now. See, we're building this.
激光护盾
Laser shield.
它可以把一切都挡在外面
It'll keep all the creeters out.
我们就躲在这里 然后用现有的资源应付生活
And we'll just tuck right in here and make do with what we've got.
应付？不 等等 你不明白 指挥官
Make do? No. Wait. But you don't understand, Commander.
我可以继续干 得以让我们离开这里
I can still do it. I can get us outta here.
老兄 你还相信这一点 真是太好了
Man, it's great you still believe that.
但我们现在也不错
But we're good, Buzz.
特别是有了激光护盾
Got the laser shield.
哦 你好 巴斯
Oh. Hello, Buzz.
巴斯？
Buzz?
我有个好消息 巴斯
Well, I've got some good news, Buzz.
我解决了燃料的问题
I figured out the fuel problem.
什么？
What?
这是一个有意思的组合
It was an interesting combination.
仅仅是有很小的差异 但就造成了很大的差别
Just the slightest variance, but that made all the difference.
索克斯 你是怎么做到的？
Sox, how did you do this?
我花了62年7个月又5天
It took me 62 years, seven months and five days.
它很稳定？
And it's stable?
理论上是的
Theoretically.
我期待着在你的下一次任务中得到答案
I look forward to finding out on your next mission.
是啊...
Yeah...
什么？
What?
晚上好 队长 我们是来接你的机器人伴侣的
Evening, Captain. We're here to pick up your companion robot.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
基于安全原因 你懂的
Security purposes. You understand.
不 实际上 我不懂
No, actually, I don't.
我们要关掉程序 就是说 必须要让你的猫退役
Shutting down the program, So, we have to decommission your cat.
只需要一下下
It'll just take a second.
等等 至少...
Now, hold on, just...
至少让我来做
At least let me do it.
哇？
Whoa?
巴斯 我们要去哪里？
Buzz. Where are we going?
我们要去太空
We're going to space.
什么？
What?
巴斯光年的任务日志 星际日期...
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date...
我也不知道
I have no idea.
在拥有稳定的燃料配方的情况下
In possession of stable fuel formula
我计划进行光速飞行 以便最终完成任务
I plan to reach hyper-speed and this time finally finish the mission.
你在和谁说话？
Who are you talking to?
不重要
Doesn't matter.
巴斯 我的程序强迫我通知星际指挥部你的离开...
Buzz, my programming compels me to notify Star Command that you have gone--
星际指挥部打算让你退役
Star Command was gonna decommission you.
-什么？
-What? -That's right.
关掉你 所以就没有索克斯了
Lights out. No more Sox.
嘿 你没有得到进入这个区域的授权
Hey! You're not authorized to be in this area--
哇 我不知道你还能干这个
Whoa, I didn't know you could do that.
等等 这是为我准备的 以防我越界？
Wait a minute, was that for me in case I got out of line?
我给你争取了5分钟
I bought you five minutes.
-好吧 索克斯 给我第一个 -收到
-All right, Sox, give me the first one. -Roger.
好了 开始吧
Okay, here it goes.
哇
Wow.
配方！
The formula!
探戈呼叫基地 探戈呼叫基地 发射区存在安全漏洞
Tango to Base. Tango to Base. Security breach in the launch peg.
该死
Blast.
我们有警卫倒下 重复一遍 我们有警卫倒下
We have a guard down. Repeat. We have a guard down.
好的
Okay.
你好
Hello.
-我是你的内置声控导航仪 -不！I. V. A. N. ！不
-I'm your internal voice-activated navigator. -No! I.V.A.N.! No.
-你听到了吗？-叫我I.V.A.N
-Do you hear that? -Call me I.V.A.N.
任务控制中心 在XL-15检查到异常情况
Mission Control, activity detected in XL-15.
正在调查
Investigating.
收到
Roger that.
XL-15 这里是控制中心
XL-15, this is the control.
里面有人吗？
Is there someone in there?
-说点儿什么 -XL-15
-Say something. -XL-15.
请回答
Please respond.
收到 控制室 只是... ... 清洁人员
Copy, control. Just... the cleaning crew.
我们正在清洁驾驶舱 在这是清洁物品？
We're cleaning the cockpit. Cleaning items in here?
指挥官 我们是否批准了XL-15的驾驶舱清洁工作？
Commander, did we authorize the cockpit cleaning for the XL-15?
什么？没有
What? No.
-停下！回来！-等等！
-Stop! Come back! -Wait!
XL-15 你违反了星际指挥部的规定
XL-15, you are in violation of Star Command protocol.
立即停止你的行动
Cease your actions immediately.
打开舱门！
Open this hatch!
指挥官 我是光年船长
Commander, it's Captain Lightyear.
等等 什么？是光年？把他弄出来！
Wait? What? Lightyear? Get him out of there!
马上停下 把你的手放在头上！
Stop right now and put your hands over your head!
增援
Back up.
-我们需要增援 -让扎普巡逻队来
-We need back up. -Get the Zap patrol.
好了 伙计们 我们上
All right, team. Let's go.
关闭发射舱门 他哪儿也去不了
Override the silo doors. He isn't going anywhere.
该死
Blast.
未授权
Unauthorized.
-未授权 -我们这样是坐以待毙
-Unauthorized. -Come on, we're sitting ducks here.
让我来
Allow me.
-等等 发生了什么？-他接管了我的控制
-Wait, what's happening? -He overrode my override.
怎么会？
How?
光年！
Lightyear!
我知道你能听到我
I know you can hear me.
马上把飞船送回基地!
Return the ship to base right now!
否则我就...
Or so help me--
索克斯 我们要打破光速屏障 带大家回家
Sox, let's break this hyper-speed barrier and get everyone home.
接近70%光速
Approaching 70 percent hyper-speed.
接近80%光速
Approaching 80 percent hyper-speed.
燃料稳定
Fuel stable.
90%光速
Ninety percent hyper-speed.
100%光速
One hundred percent hyper-speed.
恭喜你 光年船长
Congratulations, Captain Lightyear.
你已经到达了光速
You have achieved hyper-speed.
我们成功了 索克斯 我们成功了！
We did it. Sox, we did it!
恭喜你 巴斯
Congratulations, Buzz.
真是太可怕了 我都后悔入伙了
That was utterly terrifying, and I regret having joined you.
不 不
No, no.
怎么了 巴斯？
What is it, Buzz?
我们的速度仍然非常高
Our velocity is still extremely high.
什么？哦 不！
What? Oh no!
我们会坠毁吗？
Are we gonna crash?
不会
No.
好吧 技术上说是的 坚持住
Well, technically yes. Just hang on.
经过这么多年的努力 谢谢你 索克斯
After all these years. Thank you, Sox.
任务补充日志
Mission log, supplemental.
从星际指挥部借来一艘飞船后 我已经实现了光速飞行
After borrowing a ship from Star Command I've achieved hyper-speed.
我已经准备好最终离开这个星球
And I'm ready to finally leave this planet once and for all.
巴斯光年呼叫星际指挥部 请回话 星际指挥部
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command. Come in, Star Command.
星际指挥部 请回话
Star Command, come in.
他们为什么不回答？
Why don't they answer?
嘿！
Hey!
有机器人
The robots.
有什么？
The what?
机器人
The robots.
等等 它在干什么？
Wait, what's it doing?
佐格.
Zurg.
-我的飞船！-安静
-My ship! -Be quiet.
它去哪了？
Where'd it go?
去上面了
Up there.
佐格
Zurg.
飞行员去哪儿了？
Where is the pilot?
那是什么？发生了什么？
What is that? What is going on?
蹲下
Get down.
跟我来
Shoot! Come on.
他们一定也看到了你的飞船着陆
They must have seen your ship land too.
-谁？-那些机器人
-Who? -The robots.
为什么会有机器人？机器人是从哪里来的？
Why are there robots? Where did the robots come from?
你是从哪儿来的？
Where did you come from?
我是从这儿来的
I came from here.
从这儿？等等
Here? Wait.
巴斯？
Buzz?
阿利沙？
Alisha?
哦 不 那是我奶奶 我是依奇
Oh, no, that's my grandmother. I'm Izzy.
依奇？
Izzy?
当时你只是个小...
But you were just a little...
索克斯 我们离开多久了？
Sox, how long were we gone?
喵喵
Meow meow.
22年 19周又4天
Twenty-two years, 19 weeks and four days.
哇
Wow.
等等
Wait.
来吧
Come on.
来这儿
In here.
我想我听到有一个
I thought I heard one.
-机器人？-是的
-A robot? -Yeah.
令人印象深刻
Impressive.
我可是霍桑家的人
Well, I am a Hawthorne.
当然
You sure are.
你知道吗 你奶奶和我几乎可以接上对方的话
You know, your grandma and I could practically finish each other's sentences.
如果你像她一样 你和我就会成为--
If you're anything like her, you and I are gonna make--
-...一个伟大的团队 -...机器人会哭鼻子
-...a great team. -...some robots cry.
好吧...
Okay...
所以 让我尽快了解这个
So, get me up to speed on this.
好的 佐格飞船大约一周前出现的
Right. The Zurg ship showed up about a week ago.
佐格是什么?
What's a Zurg?
机器人只会说这个 所以我们就叫它大船
That's the only thing the robots say, so that's what we call the big ship.
佐格飞船来后 机器人包围了基地 然后... ...
The Zurg ship arrived, the robots surrounded the base, and then...
塔卡尼主星的公民们 我们遭到了外星机器人的袭击
Citizens of T'kani Prime, robot aliens have attacked.
大家都在里边
Everyone inside the perimeter.
小心！
Look out!
我们马上启动激光护盾
We are activating the laser shield immediately.
这就是我们最后得到的消息
And that's the last we heard.
所有这些人 他们都指望着我
All these people, they were counting on me.
而现在他们被困住了
And now they're trapped.
我们试图联系他们 但没有通信 不管是向内还是向外
We've tried to reach them, but there's no communication, in or out.
索克斯？
Sox?
喵喵 她说对了
Meow meow. She's correct.
你的猫还能验证我说的话?
Did you check me against your cat?
他不是你印象中的猫
Well, he's not your standard-issue feline.
事实上 索克斯是你奶奶送的礼物
Actually, Sox was a gift from your grandmother.
-你好 依奇 -你好 索克斯
-Hello, Izzy. -Hello, Sox.
嘿 那是什么声音? 小心点 别把猫弄坏了
Hey, what's that noise? Come on, don't break my cat.
他在咕噜咕噜 他就喜欢这样
He's purring. He likes it.
索克斯 你喜欢吗？
Sox, do you like it?
喜欢
I do.
好吧 我希望你已经准备参与行动了 因为我们需要一个飞行员
Well, I hope you're ready for action. Because all we needed was a pilot.
做什么？
For what?
我有一个计划并且我还有一个团队
I have a plan and I have a team.
来吧！
Come on!
伙计们 集合了
All right, team, fall in.
我找到了个飞行员 惊喜派对行动要开始了
I found a pilot. Operation Surprise Party is a go.
我喜欢 一个精英小队 精英中的精英
I like this. An elite squad. The best of the best.
你们知道吗 她奶奶是历史上最伟大的太空游侠
You know, her grandmother was the greatest Space Ranger in the history of the Corps.
能和你一起共事将是一种荣誉
It will be an honor to work with you.
来吧 到这边来 伙计们
Come on, gather round, team.
让我们回顾一下我们的目标
Let's review our objectives.
干掉那些机器人
Kill the robots.
还有不要死
And don't die.
"不要死 "是你每天都要做做到的
"Don't die" is just something you wanna do every day.
这仍然是一个目标
It's still an objective.
如果可以的话 我们有还有一个目标
If I may, we have one objective.
我们需要把这个晶体装进萝卜号里 然后离开这里
We need to put this crystal in the turnip and get outta here.
所以 要做到这一点 我们必须进入基地
So, to do that we have to get onto the base.
要做到这一点 我们必须杀死所有的机器人
To do that we have to kill all the robots.
要做到这一点 我们必须摧毁佐格飞船
To do that we have to destroy the Zurg ship.
而要做到这些 我们就必须不死
And to do any of that we have to not die.
DERIC
让我解释一下什么是惊喜派对行动
Allow me to explain Operation Surprise Party.
它是雷霆之矛行动的一个变种
It is a variation on Operation Thunder Spear.
你不是还因为那次行动得到了一枚奖章吗？
Didn't you get a medal for that one?
实际上是两枚 但是...
Two, actually, but...
等等 你是怎么知道雷霆之矛行动的？
Wait, how do you know about Operation Thunder Spear?
我读过我奶奶所有的太空游侠的书 从头读到尾
I've read all my grandma's Space Ranger books, from cover to cover.
而且是两遍
Twice.
对不起 机器人猫咪
Excuse me, robot kitty.
哦 对不起
Oh, sorry.
感应器显示佐格飞船为地面上的机器人提供动力
Sensors have indicated that the Zurg ship powers the robots on the ground.
所以 我们飞到那里 炸毁那艘船 给机器人一个大大的惊喜！
So, we fly up there, we blow up the ship. And surprise, robots!
你们要变烤面包了
You're toast.
然后 我们把你的晶体装进萝卜号里
Then, we put your crystal in the turnip.
然后任务就完成了
And finish the mission.
这是个好计划 飞向宇宙
It's a good plan. To infinity.
你想让我碰你的手指吗？
Are you trying to get me to pull your finger?
别上当了
Don't fall for it.
不 不是这样的 是...
No, not like that, it was...
对不起 这是你奶奶和我过去常干的
Sorry, it's a thing your grandma and I used to do.
恶心
Ew.
我... 我们从来没有... 她不是...
I-- We were never-- She didn't mean to...
总之 算了吧 我们继续
Anyway, forget it. Moving on.
我们把这些弹药装到犰狳号上
Let's load these munitions into the Armadillo
并准备好战斗
and steel ourselves for combat.
惊喜派对行动开始了
Operation Surprise Party is on.
巴斯 你听到什么吗？
Buzz, do you hear that?
我听到有什么动静
I hear something.
你觉得是机器人吗？
You think it's a robot?
不 我们从来没有在离基地这么远的地方见过机器人
Nah, we've never seen a robot this far from the base.
我怎么什么都没听到
I don't hear anything.
现在听到了
Now I do.
佐格.
Zurg.
别担心 我们会救你
Don't worry, we got you.
怎么？
What?
训练用弹药
TRAINING AMMO
不要害怕！预备役巡逻队救你回来
Fear not! The Junior Patrol has your back.
什么预备役？
The Junior what?
不 飞船！
No! The ship!
射中了吗？
Did I get it?
很接近
Pretty close.
对不起 我没有受过这种武器的训练
Sorry, I'm not trained with this weapon.
我重新装弹
Let me reload.
没受过训练？等等 你说你 "没有受过训练 "是什么意思？
Not trained? Wait, what do you mean you're "not trained"?
你在那里 抓住它！抓住它！
You there. Grab it! Grab it!
抓住什么？
Grab what?
我不能触碰武器
I'm not allowed to handle weapons
这违反我的假释规定
the violation of my parole.
假释？
Parole?
巴斯！
Buzz!
依奇！就现在！
Izzy! Now!
不！
No!
好吧 我有个新计划
Okay, new plan.
新计划？旧计划是什么？
New plan? What was the old plan?
我需要... 有人看到鱼叉了吗？
I need the-- Anyone seen the harpoons?
他们准备了一个鱼叉 但我找不到... ...
They came preloaded with a harpoon, but I can't find--
哦 我找到了
Oh, I found it.
我找到了鱼叉 我现在要重新装上它 看看这个吧
I found the harpoons. I'm gonna reload it now. Check this out.
射中了吗？
Did I get it?
再往左一点点
A little to the left.
什么？
What?
射中了吗？
Did I get it?
射中了
You got it.
是的！
Yes!
轰隆隆
Boom.
好吧 好吧 到底是什么... ... 这一切...
Okay, okay. What exactly-- How did that--
你们到底是谁？
Who are you?
我们是预备役巡逻队 为你服务
We're the Junior Patrol, at your service.
我需要了解更多情况
Right, I'm gonna need more information.
我们是一支由上进的学员组成的志愿者队伍
We are a volunteer team of self-motivated cadets.
我们每个月在前哨站这里训练一个星期
We train one week in a month here at the outpost.
莫 达比和我是上周末机器人出现时
Mo and Darby and I were the first to arrive last weekend
首批抵达的
when the robots showed up.
所以 我们策划了惊喜派对行动
So, we cooked up Operation Surprise Party.
那么说 你们都是菜鸟咯？
So, you are rookies?
老兄 我们倒是想成为菜鸟呢 但现在我们连菜鸟都不够格
Boy, we'd love to be rookies, still building up to that.
好的 你们有弹药训练吗？
Okay. Do you have munitions training?
-只有一部分 -你们做过战术训练吗？
-Partial. -Tactical engagement?
-还没有 -有战斗经验呢？
-Pending. -Combat experience?
是的！如果我们刚刚跟机器人的那次算数的话
Yes! If you count the robot situation we just went through.
好的 来吧 索克斯
Okay. Come on, Sox.
你这是干什么？
What are you doing?
听着 你们看来是好人
Look, you seem nice people.
我非常支持你们的训练计划
I'm very supportive of your training initiatives.
但我还是得从今往后独自行动
But I'm gonna go ahead and take it from here.
可我们刚刚从机器人手里救了你
We just saved you from that robot.
-怎么说？-莫完成了致命一击
-Excuse me? -Mo made the kill shot.
莫的确很幸运
Mo got lucky.
非常幸运
Very.
那么 如果们能告诉我另外一艘飞船在哪
So, if you could just point me in the direction of another ship.
在废弃仓库里有可用的飞船
There are operational spacecrafts at the abandoned storage depot.
很好 那是哪儿？
Great. Where is that?
仓库就在资源重组中心旁边
The storage depot is directly adjacent to the Resource Reconstituting Center,
距你现在的位置有4.2公里
which is 4.2 kilometers from your current location.
棒极了 那又是哪儿？
Great. Where is that?
很简单
It's actually quite simple.
好吧
Okay.
首先向南朝着基地前进
You will first head south towards the base.
经过两个红绿灯后 然后...
After two stop lights you will--
等一下 不对 那是死路
Wait, that is not right. That is a dead end.
哦 我明白了 我走错了
Oh, I see, I was in the wrong spot.
对不起 我重来
Apologies. I will start over.
首先向南朝着基地前进
You will first head south towards the base.
过了两个红绿灯后 稍往左转 然后... ...
After two stop lights you'll take a gentle left and--
哎呀 我又错了
Shoot. I have made another error.
我们带你去吧
We'll just show you.
请允许再说一次
Allow me to restart.
首先向南朝着基地前进
You will first head south towards the base.
过了两个红绿灯后 向右转...
After two stop lights you'll take a hard right...
巴斯光年任务补充日志
Buzz Lightyear supplemental mission log.
在最终实现光速飞行后
Having finally achieved hyper-speed
却又多了一个障碍
I now have an additional obstacle in my way.
为了逃离这个星球 我必须独自摧毁一艘巨大的外星飞船
In order to flee this planet I'll have to destroy a massive alien ship alone.
没有任何形式的协助
with no assistance of any kind.
你知道的 我们能帮忙 这是我们的计划
You know, we can help you. It is our plan.
我不允许这样
I can't allow that.
星际命令代号2709.3
Star Command Code 2709.3
禁止我置无资格的人员于危险境地
forbids me from placing unqualified personnel in harms way.
好吧 但我可是霍桑家的
Okay, but I'm a Hawthorne.
这可不只是个家族名 依奇
It's more than just a name, Izzy.
你必须清楚地知道...
You have to know exactly--
-在面对任何情况下的反应... ...你接下来会说什么
-...how to react in any sit-- -...what you gonna say next.
我想我能做到
I thought I had that one.
好的
Okay.
那么你 现在是在参与某种行为矫正?
And you, you're in a correctional situation of some kind?
假释计划
Parole program.
我参与这个 他们给我减刑
I do this and they shave a little time off my sentence.
但我在那里真的学到了很多东西
But I really learned a lot in there.
达比可以把任何三样东西混在一起让它们爆炸
Darby can take any three things and make them explode.
好的 那你呢？ - 我？
Okay. And what about you?
我以为就是一个好玩的训练营
Me? I thought this was gonna be like a fun boot camp workout thing.
但并不是
But it is not.
所以 我实际上是来这里是纯付出...
So, I was actually coming out here to turn in my stuff--
他是个逃兵
He's a quitter.
我不是逃兵
I'm not a quitter.
你就是逃兵
You were quitting.
你说什么呢？我只是往另一个方向前进而已
What are you talking about? I was just going in a different direction.
是啊 逃兵的方向
Yeah, the direction of a quitter.
好吧 我不说了
You know what, I give up.
-你们看见了吧 往右拐...
-See? -On your right..
佐格
Zurg.
现在 我到哪儿了？
Now, where was I?
哦在这 我得往回走
Here we are. Let me back up.
继续进行技能训练 这是让你们变强的唯一方法
Hey, keep working on your skills. It's the only way to get better.
我们能帮你
We can help you.
很感激 只要你们回到训练场去
And I appreciate that. Just go back to your training facility.
保持警惕 保证安全
Stay alert. Stay safe.
我去征用这P-32犰狳号
I'm going to commandeer this P-32 Armadillo
然后去炸掉佐格的船
and go blow up the Zurg ship.
那么 这是在告别？
So, this is just goodbye?
是啊 再见吧
Affirmative. Goodbye.
对不起 忘了我的猫
Sorry, I forgot my cat.
检测到生命体
Life forms detected.
是什么？
What are they?
巨大的昆虫
Giant insectoid organisms.
这座建筑似乎是某种巢穴
The building appears to be some sort of hive.
有威胁吗？
Are they a threat?
传感器显示它们正在冬眠
Sensors indicate they are hibernating.
非常好
Very good.
哦 看！
Oh, look!
是XL-01
It's the XL-01.
已经很久没有...
It's been a long time since...
哇哦
Whoa.
那是什么？
What is it?
来 我带你看看
Come on, I'll show you.
终于
Finally.
对不起 打断一下
Sorry to interrupt.
看起来你正在享受美好的时刻
Looks like you were having a real nice moment.
你在这儿干什么？这儿不安全
What are you doing here? It's not safe.
你带走了我们的车钥匙
You took the keys to our truck.
在这儿呢
There they are.
拜托 拜托 拜托
Come on. Come on.
-安静 -我倒是想呢
-Quiet. -I'm trying.
搞定了
Got it.
-谁去... ... -关门！
-Somebody get-- -Get the door!
你想说"关门" 而我已经关门了
You were gonna say "get the door", and I got the door.
好吧 我就直说了吧 真希望这事没发生
Well, I'm gonna be blunt here. I wish that hadn't happened.
我们也一样
So did the rest of us.
大家拿上武器
Everyone grab a weapon.
孩子 我也想 但我的假释...
Boy, I'd love to, but my parole--
作为一名星际指挥官 我授予你紧急权力
As a Star Command Officer I grant you emergency authority.
我们要冲出这里
We're gonna blast our way outta here.
现在我们只是在喋喋不休
Now we're talking!
巴斯 正面攻击的生存概率是38. 2%
Buzz, the probability of survival a frontal attack is 38.2 percent.
似乎有点低
Seems a bit low.
那隐身模式呢？
What about Stealth Mode?
你怎么知道隐身模式的？
How do you know about Stealth Mode?
奶奶和我以前总是在玩隐身模式
Grandma and I used to play Stealth Mode all the time.
这就像捉迷藏 但有点作弊嫌疑
It was like hide-and-seek, but with a twist.
好的 其实这是不错的想法 我使用隐身模式来迷惑他们
Okay, well, it's actually good thinking. I'll use Stealth Mode to disorient them.
或者 用我的办法
Or, and stick with me here.
我们都使用隐身模式 然后直接走出去
We could all use Stealth Mode and just walk right out.
你是说 你要穿太空游侠的制服？
You mean, you would wear a Space Ranger suit?
这制服上已经有我的名字了
This one already has my name on it.
好吧
Okay.
让我们捋一下
Let's review.
我去...
I'm going--
那边儿
That way.
而你们要去...
And you're going--
那边儿
That way.
好的 非常好
Okay. Very good.
看呐 我是费瑟... 费瑟林... ...
Check it out, I'm Feathers... Feathering...
哦 看 是支笔 真酷
Oh, look, a pen. Cool.
-你的有笔吗？-好了 注意了
-Does yours have a pen? -Okay, pay attention.
隐身模式是相当简单的
Stealth mode is fairly simple.
只有两个要点 按下这个按钮--
There are just two parts. You press the button--
-是这个按钮吗？-我会告诉你哪个按钮
-Is it this button? -I will tell you which button.
-那这个按钮呢？-我很抱歉
-What about this button? -I'm sorry.
我们没有时间去了解所有的按钮了
We're not gonna have time to go over all the buttons.
好吧 忘掉按钮 那这个东西呢？
Okay, forget the button. What about this thing?
-它更-- -不！不！ 不！
-It's more-- -No! No!
那是投降拉环 你千万别拉那个
That's the surrender strand. You never pull that.
对于太空游侠来说 没有比这更可耻的举动了
There is no more shameful maneuver for a Space Ranger.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我还是没搞清哪个是隐身模式的按钮？
Did I miss which button is the Stealth Mode button?
是这个
It's this button.
现在别按!
Not yet!
按下这个按钮 然后就从前门走出去
You push this button, then you go out the front door,
然后我就去炸掉佐格飞船
and I'll go blow up the Zurg ship.
-准备好了吗？-准备好了
-Ready? -Ready.
不 等等 还没准备好 等一下
No, wait. Not ready. Hang on.
好了 拿上了 要不就尴尬了
Okay, got 'em. That would've been embarrassing.
好
Okay.
再见了
Goodbye again.
索克斯 你挡住了我的视线
Sox, you're inhibiting my visual.
对不起 这样好点儿吗？
Sorry. Is this better?
-不好 -好吧 这样如何？
-Negative. -Okay, how about this?
不如这样？
How about this?
好 我们到了
Okay. Here we go.
非常好 隐形模式工作得很好
Very good. Stealth Mode working as planned.
这真是酷 这些傻虫子看不见我们
This is pretty cool. These dumb bugs can't even see us.
嘿 虫子 嘿 虫子 傻虫子
Hey, bug. Hey, bug. Bug.
我在这儿 傻虫子 你看不见我吧？
I'm right here, bug. Can't you see me?
看不见 他根本就看不见我
He can't. He can't see me at all.
时间到了
And time has elapsed.
等等 定时器
Wait, the timer.
他们不知道有定时器
They don't know about the timer.
你看不见我
You don't see me.
等等 我看见你了
Wait. I can see you.
我也看见你了
I can see you too.
虫子看见我们了
The bugs can see us.
不 不 我投降
No, no. I surrender.
推!
Pull!
后退！后退！
Back! Back!
这不行
This isn't working.
你们得往前走！
You have to keep going!
我们得调头
We have to turn around.
他们冲我们过来了
They're headed right for us.
别 别 别靠近飞船！
No, no. Do not approach the vehicle!
很好！
All right!
-良好的团队合作 -来击个掌
-Way to adapt, team. -Give it up here.
你们在庆祝什么？
Why are you congratulating yourselves?
因为我刚刚用霍桑家的方式救了大家
Because I just Hawthorned us out right outta that situation.
但你本可以做得...
But you could've made it if--
如果你告诉我们隐身模式会失效
If you had told us the Stealth Mode wears off.
好吧...
Well...
好了 大家系好安全带
Okay, everyone just strap in.
你好 我是你的...
Hello, I am your--
抓紧了！
Hold on!
我们要上太空了？
Are we going to space?
不 我会把你们放在某个地方
No, I'm gonna drop you somewhere.
转得太厉害了 我想要个呕吐袋
That was a big swirly turn. I think I need a bag.
不 不 不要在飞船里吐
No, no. Do not vomit inside the vehicle.
我可以看到星星了 这是太空
I can see stars. That is space.
这是怎么了？
What is happening right now?
她害怕太空
She's afraid of space.
-什么？ -她有道理 是太可怕了
-What? -She should be. It's horrible
依奇 记住你曾经的训练
Izzy, remember your exercises.
-我要吐了 -不 不
-It's coming. -No, no.
把你的头盔关上 吐头盔里
Engage your helmet. That will catch it.
-巴斯！那有艘飞船！-依奇 我正尝试... ...
-Buzz! Another ship! -Izzy, I'm trying--
我什么都看不见了
I can't see anything.
哦 不！是行星的暗面
Oh, no! The dark side of the planet.
在那儿！三点钟方向！
Over there! Three o'clock!
坚持住 这不太好
Hold on. This isn't gonna be pretty.
大家都还好吗？
Is everyone okay?
我想是的
I think so.
索克斯 给我一份损坏报告
Sox, give me a damage report.
请稍等
One moment, please.
好 好多了
Okay. This is better.
这算好多了?
Is this better?
不 显然整体上还很糟糕 我只我说... 你懂的...
No, obviously this is worse overall, I just meant... You know...
你怎么会害怕太空？
How are you afraid of space?
哦 这很简单
Oh, It's pretty easy.
你知道放任不管的话，就会朝一个方向发展吗
Did you know if you let go out there you just keep going in the same direction
一直发展 只是...
forever, just...
好吧 那你打算怎么炸掉佐格飞船？
Well, then how were you going to blow up the Zurg ship?
我本来是做地面支援的
I would've been ground support.
我知道 奶奶并不害怕太空
I know, grandma wasn't afraid of space.
不 因为她是一名太空游侠
No, because she was a Space Ranger.
天体恐惧症是会自动被取消资格的
Astrophobia is an automatic disqualification.
刚才那是什么东西？
What was that thing?
-我不知道 -它还会回来吗？
-I don't know. -Is it gonna come back?
我不知道
I don't know.
但它是怎么... ... 好吧 你不知道
But how did it-- Okay, you don't know.
我本来已经完成了 终于得到了晶体 本该结束一切的
I was done. I finally had the crystal. This was supposed to be over.
但骗谁呢？
But who am I kidding?
我需要的根本不是什么晶体
I don't need a crystal.
我需要一台时间机器来摆脱这场混乱
I need a time machine to get out of this mess.
评估完成
Assessment complete.
情况有多糟？
How bad is that?
爆炸被热护盾吸收了 仅仅造成了轻微的电气短路
The blast was absorbed by the heat shield and only caused a minor electrical short.
好的
Okay.
那么 为了能继续飞行
So, in order to be flight operational
犰狳号需要一种特殊电容
the Armadillo will require a material of specialized capacitance.
哦 听起来像电气有关的东西
Oh, like an electrical thingy.
你还懂这个？
How do you know that?
我们学过
We learned this.
特殊电容 记得吗？我们上个月做的野外收音机？
Specialized capacitance, remember? We built those field radios last month?
哦 是的 很有意思
Oh, yeah. That was fun.
是的 除了达比搞砸了
Yeah, except Darby messed hers up.
我要把你搞砸--
I'm gonna mess you up--
拜托 我正在思考
Please. I'm trying to think here.
我搞砸了 但我又把它修好了
I messed mine up, but then I fixed it up.
但是你弄坏了电脑控制台
But you broke that computer console.
我需要那个小... 什么来着？
I needed that little coil for its... What was that?
特殊电容
Specialized capacitance.
嘿 说实话 这儿这么大的地方
Hey, honestly, there is a lot of room out here.
如果你们要回忆旧事 可以到那边去
If you guys wanna reminisce you could go over there,
或者看看 那边儿没人正在思考
or look, there's no one trying to think over there.
我们可以到上面去
We can go up there.
好吧 完美
Fine. Perfect.
是的 好的 有新计划
Yes. Okay, new plan.
等等 什么？
Wait. What?
那个采矿设施会有一个控制台 对吗？
That mining facility will have a console, right?
那个控制台会有一个小线圈 对吗？
That console will have a little coil thing, right?
而那个小线圈会有...
And that little coil thing will have the...
特殊电容
Specialized capacitance.
我们需要修复这艘飞船 对吧？
That we need to fix this ship, right?
她说得对
She's right.
做得好 这才是霍桑家人的思维方式
Good job. Now that's thinking like a Hawthorne.
我们去拿那个零件 然后离开这里
Let's go get that part and get outta here
在那东西再次找到我们之前
before that thing finds us again.
哇
Whoa.
那边
Over there.
好了 我们走吧
Okay, here we go.
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
为了修复飞船 我们必须找到方法
In order to repair our ship we have to find some way
进入指挥中心并...
to get inside the Command Center and...
干得好 老犯人
Nice job, elderly convict.
好的 线圈应该在这里
Okay, the activation coil should be in here.
索克斯？
Sox?
需要笔吗？
Need a pen?
拿到了
Got it.
好吧 下次吧
Okay, yeah. Another time.
哦 不
Oh no.
安全措施启动
Security measures activated.
不 别又来一次
No! Not this again.
什么又来？这是什么？
Not what? What is this?
捕获锥 在他们来抓你之前 它能限制你行动
A capture cone. That holds you until they come and get you.
没人会来救我们 他们都被困在基地里呢
No one's coming to get us. They're all trapped in the base.
所以 我们应该离开这儿 对吧？
So, we should just leave, right?
我们走不了的
We can't just leave.
当然可以 听我说 我们可以离开的
Sure we can. Take it from me, we can always just leave.
看到了吗？
Look, see?
不是吧！
Come on!
我都说过了
Told you.
现在 小心点 因为这些东西 --
Now, be careful, because these things--
如果它们互相接触 就会合并在一起
combine if they touch.
好吧 对不起 但也许我们两个一起试一下？
All right, sorry. But maybe if we both try it?
那是不行的
That's not gonna work.
你试都没试
You haven't even tried.
不！
No!
喵喵
Meow.
是的 不行
Yeah, that didn't work.
-巴斯？-哇 别动
-Buzz? -Whoa, hold on.
如果我和你们被困在一起 那就帮不上忙了
I'm no help to anyone if I'm stuck in there with you.
索克斯 你能把这些关掉吗？
Sox, can you turn these off?
我够不到控制装置
I can't reach the controls.
等等 这里的地面软软的
Wait, there's a soft spot in the floor here.
-或许我们可以... -那是我的脚
-Maybe if we could-- -That's my foot.
-对不起 -等等 小心！
-Sorry. -Wait, watch it!
等等 就是这个 那东西给这东西提供电源
Wait, that's it. That thing powers these things.
-那我们就再撞一次 -等等 等一下
-Then let's hit it again. -Wait. Wait.
我们需要开门
We need the door to be open.
我负责开门 你们狠狠地撞那个电源
So I'll open this. You slam into the power source.
这东西会消失 那么我们就可以出去了
These things will disappear. And we'll walk right out.
-是的 先生 -好的
-Yes, sir. -All right.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
继续！
Keep trying!
我们还不够重
We're just not heavy enough.
巴斯 我们需要你
Buzz, we need you.
等等 到那里边去？
Wait, in there?
但如果不成功 我就不能救你们了
But if it doesn't work I won't be able to save you.
你不需要救我们 你需要加入我们
You don't need to save us, you need to join us.
再来一次
Again.
再来！
Again!
不！
No!
走！快走！
Go! Go!
小心！
Watch out!
巴斯 不要！
Buzz, no!
我们需要线圈
We need the coil.
我们抓住你了
We got you.
哦 看呐 有零食
Oh, look. Snacks.
有人要吃零食吗？
Anyone going for the snack?
肉类三明治
MEAT SANDWICH
这里 我们补充点能量吧
Here. Let's all re-charge a little.
给
Here you go.
嗯 这是 呃--什么--什么--
Huh, this is, uh-- What-- What's--
这里发生了什么？
What's happening here?
你的三文治有什么问题？
Something wrong with your sandwich?
为什么肉在外面？
Why is the meat on the outside?
因为它是三明治？
Because it's a sandwich?
不 面包应该是在外面的
No, the bread is supposed to be on the outside.
什么 面包 肉 面包？
What, like, bread, meat, bread?
那面包就太多了
That's too much bread.
是的 但这湿呼呼的
Yes, but this is all wet.
是的 沾满汁水的手指 那可是精华部分
Yeah. Juicy fingers. That's the best part.
你上次吃三明治是什么时候？
When was the last time you had a sandwich?
我不知道 差不多 一百年前吧
I don't know, a hundred years ago, give or take.
那只是 "面包 肉 面包"
Just a "bread, meat, bread."
那面包就太多了
That's too much bread.
会把你嘴里的水分都吸走
That would just suck all the moisture out of your mouth.
说得好 达比
Good one, Darby.
哦 不！
Oh, no!
索克斯！
Sox!
醒醒 索克斯
Wake up, Sox.
来吧 小兄弟 醒过来吧
Come on, little buddy, come back to me.
拜托 索克斯 对不起
Please, Sox. I'm sorry.
索克斯
Sox.
你好 我需要重启
Hello. I require a reboot.
我很抱歉 伙计们 我差点杀了索克斯
I'm sorry, guys. I almost killed Sox.
我差点把我们都害死了
I almost got us all killed back there.
嘿 听我说 这只是一个小插曲
Hey, listen to me, it was just a mistake.
对吧 巴斯？
Right, Buzz?
尝试让自己做得更好吧
Just try to get a little better.
听着
Listen.
我只是...
I just...
当我第一次去游侠学院的时候 我做得并不... 你知道的... 并不好
When I first went to the Academy I was not... you know... good.
我每天都搞砸事情
I screwed up every day.
我在障碍赛中弄得一团糟
I got tangled in the obstacle course.
我的手抖得厉害 无法打中靶子
My hands shook so much I couldn't hit the target.
都还别说靶心 是无法打中靶子
Not the bulls-eye. The whole target.
一周后 我就打算退出 因为... ...
And I was gonna quit after the first week, it was...
我显然不是做太空游侠的料
clear I was not Space Ranger material.
真吗？
Really?
是的
Yeah.
但她奶奶在我身上看到了一些东西
But her grandma saw something in me.
所以我也开始寻找它
So I started looking for it too.
重新校准
Recalibrating.
恢复了一个损坏的文件
One corrupted file restored.
嘿 他亮了
Hey, he's lighting up.
-奶奶 -你好 索克斯
-Grandma. -Hello, Sox.
我需要你帮我一个忙
I need you to do me a favor.
我需要你照顾我最好的朋友 他的名字叫巴斯
I need you to look after my best friend. His name is Buzz.
他现在不在 但他很快就会回来
He's away right now, but he'll be back soon.
他是一名太空游侠
He's a Space Ranger.
他要把我们都带回家 让我们都回家
He's going to get us all home. Get us all home.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你没听到吗？
Did not you hear that?
她相信我可以弥补我犯的错误
She believed I could fix the mistake I made.
而这种信念让她失去了一切
And that belief cost her everything.
一切？并没有
Everything? No.
她有基科奶奶 有我爸爸和我 还有她所有的朋友
She had grandma Kiko, my Dad and me, all her friends.
她本不应该在这里 但她在这个星球上得到了完整的人生 巴斯
She didn't meant to be here, but she had a whole life on this planet, Buzz.
我们所有人都是这样
All of us had.
除了你
Except for you.
我们想再次成为太空游侠 我们想变得重要
We wanted to be Space Rangers again. We wanted to matter.
相信我 她很重要
Believe me, she mattered.
你知道 这很不错
You know, it is pretty good this way.
是吗？面包 肉 面包 你这样做了多长时间？
Yeah? Bread, meat, bread. How long did you do it like that?
一直
Forever.
电已充满
Fully recharged.
来吧
Come on.
我们去把零件装回飞船 然后离开这里
Let's go put this part in the ship and get outta here.
索克斯 你能帮我们照路吗?
Sox, can you light our way?
当然
Of course.
咔嚓 咔嚓
Click click. Click click.
我看到你了 我要抓住你 抓住你
I see you. I'm gonna get ya. I'm gonna get ya.
哦 没抓住
Oh, I didn't get ya.
-索克斯？-去哪了？我抓住了！
-Sox? -Where'd you go? I got you!
-索克斯 -是的 对不起
-Sox. -Yeah, sorry.
这真是令人兴奋 惊喜派对行动 我们来了！
This is exciting. Operation Surprise Party, here we come!
等等 说什么？不行 我不能置你们于危险境地
Wait, what? Negative. I can't put you in harm's way like that.
什么 你要独自去完成任务吗？
What, are you gonna do the whole mission alone?
我能做到
I can do it.
因为你有一个霍桑家的人 就在这里
Because you got a Hawthorne right here.
我很感激 告诉你吧 如果我需要你 会让你知道的
And I appreciate that. Tell you what, I'll let you know if I need you.
但在那之前 我们先设法回到犰狳号 不要再...
But until then let's just try to get back to the Armadillo without any more--
快跑！
Run!
不！
No!
什么？
What?
它在追我！回到飞船上去！
It's after me! Go back to the ship!
但是巴斯！
But Buzz!
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
我被一个...
I'm being pursued by a...
一个巨大的机器人追
just a massive robot.
我正在引开它 让其他人逃到飞船上去
I'm leading it away while the others escape to the ship.
巴斯 -什么？
Buzz.
什么 你怎么知道我的名字？
What? How do you know my name?
到我这来
Come with me.
什么？
What?
这绝对违反了我的假释规定
This is definitely a violation of my parole.
来吧 我们离开这儿
Come on. Let's get outta here.
佐格
Zurg.
准备发射 惊喜派对行动又开始了
Ready yourselves for launch. Operation Surprise Party is back on.
什么？我们一起吗？
What? With us?
什么？ 难道让我一个人完成整个任务吗？
What, am I gonna do the whole mission alone?
还不能发射 我需要5分钟来安装线圈
We can't launch yet. I need five minutes to install the coil.
我们不能在这儿干坐5分钟
We can't sit here for five minutes.
飞船仍有悬停能力
The ship still has hover capabilities.
那我们就用上它吧
Then let's use them.
我们能在火焰喷泉那甩掉它们
We might lose them in the fire geysers.
你带路 你们两个 干掉那些机器人
Point the way. You two, blast some robots.
但我们还没有完成弹药训练
But we haven't even finished our munitions training.
这能有多难？你瞧
How hard can it be? Look.
我们有这些带刺的东西 这东西会爆炸
We got these spiky things. And these one probably explode.
只要跟着感觉来就行了
Just do whatever feels right.
什么?你打算怎么干?
What? What are you gonna do?
我要和 "炸弹先生 "跳个舞
I'm gonna dance with Mister Boom.
真令人满意
Now that's satisfying.
完成百分之二十
Twenty percent complete.
百分之？
Out of a hundred?
他们还在追 火焰喷泉在哪儿呢？
They're gaining on us. Where are those fire geysers?
就在前面
Dead ahead.
别担心 我知道每一寸...
Don't worry, I know every last inch of--
小心！
Watch out!
这儿 扔这个
Here, throw this.
-等等 等一下 -扔了它！
-Wait, hold on. -Throw it!
佐格
Zurg.
火焰喷泉就在前边！
Fire geyser dead ahead!
完成百分之五十
Fifty percent complete.
佐格
Zurg.
嘿 有个炸弹掉了！
Hey, we have explosives back here!
快！给我点什么
Quick! Give me something.
佐格
Zurg.
完成百分之九十
Ninety percent complete.
依奇 你知道如何在飞行中转移动力吗？
Izzy, do you know how to transfer power on the fly?
我已经在模拟器上做过了
I've done it in the simulator.
好吧 现在要来真的了
Well, it's about to get real.
-需要我帮忙吗？-绝对不需要
-Do you need my help with anything? -Absolutely not.
完成百分之九十五
Ninety five percent complete.
推进器准备 就是绿色按钮 中间的
Ready thrusters. Green button. Middle.
完成
Done.
记住训练中的内容
Remember from training.
不要用力扣扳机 你要轻扣扳机
You don't pull the trigger, you squeeze the trigger.
我懂的
I know.
完成百分之九十九
Ninety nine percent complete.
转移到震荡动力
Transfer to Oscillating Power.
完成
Done.
完成百分之一百
One hundred percent complete.
重新启动 好的 准备好发射
Reboot. Okay, be ready to launch
当燃料电池...
when the fuel cell is--
不！
No!
哦 不
Oh, no.
该死的！
Blast!
去拿晶体!
Grab the crystal!
不 不
No.
我...
I...
巴斯
Buzz.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
一切都发生得太快了 我...
Everything was happening so fast and I...
我只是...
I just...
我犯了错
I made a mistake.
是的
Yeah.
好吧 但我们还没有完蛋 对吗？
Okay, but we're not done, right?
我们仍然可以做些什么
We can still do something.
依奇 看看周围
Izzy, look around.
没有什么可做的
There is nothing to do.
这个任务...
The mission...
已经结束了
It's over.
巴斯
Buzz.
巴斯！
Buzz!
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我只是需要一个人静一静
I just need to be by myself.
不！
No!
巴斯！
Buzz!
Buzz.
什么鬼...
What the...
这是什么？我们在哪里？
What is this? Where are we?
你是谁？
Who are you?
这就是问题所在
Now that's the question.
你看起来不错 巴斯
You look good, Buzz.
爸爸？
Dad?
再猜猜
Guess again.
索克斯？
Sox?
你好 巴斯
Hello, Buzz.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我把这一切都搞砸了
I messed this all up.
嘿 这只是一个小插曲
Hey, it was just a mistake.
还记得你告诉我的吗？
Remember what you told me?
这次不一样
This one's different.
为什么？
Why?
因为这是我干的!
Because it's mine!
我应该和奶奶一样棒
I'm supposed to be as good as my grandma.
我本该成为像样的霍桑家传人
I'm supposed to be a Hawthorne.
但我没有
But I'm not.
巴斯？
Buzz?
等一下 等一下
Wait a minute, hold on.
你不是我 我才是我
You're not me. I am me.
你现在就是你
You are you now.
但我是50年后的你
But I'm you 50 years from now.
好吧 不可能有两个我
Well, there can't be two mes.
但我们都在这儿
Yet here we both are.
那么好吧 如果你是我
Okay then. If you're me.
我在想一个介于1和 --
I'm thinking of a number between one and--
1273.
哇哦
Whoa.
佐格
Zurg.
多可爱啊
Isn't that cute.
机器人不能清楚地说 "巴斯"
Robots can't quite say "Buzz."
所以在这里我就叫佐格
So around here I'm just Zurg.
佐格
Zurg.
我想也是你
And I guess so are you.
怎么会呢？我不明白
How? I don't understand.
别担心 这一切都不重要了
Do not worry about it. None of this is gonna matter.
巴斯
Buzz.
什么事？
Yes?
你必须向他解释这一切
You have to explain it all to him.
说得对
You're right.
很抱歉 我只是太兴奋了
I'm sorry, it's just exciting.
你终于来了
You're finally here.
看 我也达到了光速
See, I reached hyper-speed too.
光速
Hyper-speed.
和你一样
Like you did.
但我没有被当作英雄来迎接
But I wasn't greeted as a hero.
那个新指挥官要以偷窃XL-15的罪名逮捕我
No, that new Commander was gonna arrest me for stealing the XL-15.
我找到了让他们回家的方法 但他们都不在乎
I'd found a way to get them home, and they didn't even care.
所以我逃掉了
So I escaped.
我尽可能地走得远 尽可能地快
I went as far as I could, as fast as I could.
我以这种速度走了很久 已经走了几个世纪
At that speed for that long I'd traveled centuries.
而我最终来到了一个你无从得知的未来
And I ended up in a future you wouldn’t recognize.
充满了你无法想象的技术
Filled with technology you can't imagine.
就在那时 我彻底醒悟
And that's when it dawned on me.
如果我们能用这块晶体向前推进时间
If we can use this crystal to go forward in time.
为什么不能用它来回到过去呢？
Why not use it to go back?
但我们不能回到过去
But we can't go back in time.
-我们现在可以 -什么？
-We can now. -What?
听着 巴斯 我已经打破了时间
Listen, Buzz, I've broken time.
发生在你身上的事从未发生在我身上
What's happening to you never happened to me.
这是个全新的现在 从来没有过的
This is a new now that's never been lived.
你看 我们可以改变历史 巴斯
You see, we can change things, Buzz.
如果我们能回到过去 我们可以阻止自己
Well, if we can go back in time we can stop ourselves
我们可以阻止自己降落在那个星球上
from ever landing on that planet.
不撞上那座山
From ever hitting that mountain.
我们可以继续完成回家的任务
We can just continue the mission home.
而这一切都不会发生
And none of this will have ever happened.
这是个好计划
it's a good plan.
而这个晶体是这一切的关键
And this crystal is the key to it all.
等等 你不是已经有一个了吗？
Wait, don't you already have one?
嗯 算是吧
Well, sort of.
在测试时间旅行时 我把自己的晶体用光了
See, I wore my crystal out testing the time travel.
也把自己累坏了 花了不少时间
Wore myself out too. It took a while.
结果发现这并不是一门精确的科学
Turns out this isn't an exact science.
这是我能回到的最远的时间了
This is as far back in time as I could get.
来吧 帮我配置引擎
Come on, help me configure the engine.
它应该看起来很眼熟
It should look familiar.
等等 这是基于萝卜号的吗?
Wait, is this based on the turnip?
设为反转 全速
Set it for reversed thrusters, full.
那么 这些都是我们设计的？
So, we designed all of this?
不 这都是借来的
No, this is all borrowed.
我只是做了一些修改
I just made some modifications.
她又可以当太空游侠了 巴斯
She'll get to be a Space Ranger again, Buzz.
是啊
Yeah.
虽然...
Although...
什么？
What?
嗯 她不会再有家人
Well, she won't have her family.
也不会有依奇了
She won't have Izzy.
依奇是谁?
Who's Izzy?
听着 她不会想念任何人
Look, she's not gonna miss anyone
如果她一开始就没有遇到他们 对吗？
if she never meets them in the first place, right?
人们唯一得知的是我们完成了任务
The only thing people are gonna know is that we finished our mission.
把你的晶体递给我
Here. Hand me your crystal.
巴斯？
Buzz?
我不知道 也许...
I don't know, maybe...
也许我们应该考虑一下
maybe we should think about this.
考虑什么？
Think about what?
霍桑指挥官相信我们可以弥补我们犯下的这个错误
Commander Hawthorne believed we could fix this mistake we made.
而这种信念使她失去了一切
And that belief cost her everything.
哦 不 不 我们完全搞错了
Oh, no, no. We had that all wrong.
但她接下来有完整的人生
She had a whole life down there.
什么样的人生？
What kind of life?
我们应该是太空游侠
We're supposed to be Space Rangers.
我们应该是重要的
We suppose to matter.
你不会想这样生活的 巴斯
You don't wanna live like this, Buzz.
在同样的恶梦中醒来
Waking up with that same nightmare.
被你的错误所困扰
Haunted by your mistake.
你可以释怀了
But you can finally let go of that.
从现在开始
Starting right now.
你是对的
You're right.
我可以
I can.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
你和我 我们不一样
You and me, we're not the same.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不 巴斯
No, Buzz.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
嘿 猫
Hey, cat.
你知道怎么开这个东西吗？
Do you know how to fly this thing?
没有燃料了
There's no fuel.
你看 这就是我们为什么不该做超出能力的事
See, this is why we should never have gotten in over our heads.
你想做什么？
What did you wanna do?
在前哨站等着机器人找到我们？
Wait at the outpost until the robots found us?
这总比被困在这里好吧？
That's better than being stranded out here.
总比被困在没有人会找到我们的地方要好
where no one's ever gonna find us.
你是我最不想在生死关头与之为伍的人
You are the last person I wanna be stuck with in a life-and-death situation.
好吧 你很幸运 好吗？
Well, you're in luck. Okay?
看看周围 这儿没什么生 只有死
Cause look around. This is just a death situation.
喵喵
Meow meow.
我已经完全失去了巴斯的踪迹
I've completely lost Buzz.
他离得太远了 无法追踪
He's too far away to track.
各位 进去！
Everybody, inside!
什么？
What?
进飞船来
Get inside the ship.
有什么在追我们吗？
What's after us now?
我们没武器了
We don't have any more weapons.
没事 我们只是要离开这里
It's okay. We're getting out of here.
去哪里？
Where are we going?
上太空
We're going into space.
嘿 放开我 不！
Hey, let go of me. No!
我不明白这里发生了什么 巴斯
I don't understand what's happening here, Buzz.
你变了
You've changed.
而且不是变得更好
And not for the better.
不！
No!
你不能这样做 把这一切都抹杀掉
You can't do this. You're gonna erase it all.
是的
Exactly.
不 你会夺走一切
No, you gonna take away everything.
人们的家庭 他们的朋友
People's families, their friends.
我的朋友
My friends.
他们在那个星球上有自己的生活
They have lives on that planet.
每个人都是如此
Everyone does.
除了我们
Except for us.
我几乎认不出你了 巴斯
I hardly recognize you, Buzz.
这些新的想法...
All these new ideas...
你知道吗？
You know what?
我们把这些也删掉吧
We'll go ahead and erase those too.
-哇哦 -我给你争取了5分钟
-Whoa. -I bought you five minutes.
为什么？
Why?
我喜欢这个新的你
I like this new you.
我们必须摧毁这艘船
We have to destroy this ship.
你能把我带到舰桥吗？
Can you get me to the bridge?
当然可以 跟着我
Certainly. Follow me.
佐格
Zurg.
惊喜派对行动 我们来了
Operation Surprise Party, here we go.
Zap, zap!
我们需要保护我们的逃生船
We need to protect our escape ship.
所以 不要别让任何机器人从那扇门进来
So, don't let any robots come through that door.
别担心 我们会把它封住的
Don't worry, we'll seal it off.
你去找巴斯
You go find Buzz.
我会追踪他身份牌上的芯片
I'll track the chip in his dog tags.
喵喵
Meow meow.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我收到两个巴斯的信号 这不可能正确
I'm getting two Buzz signals. That's can't be right.
我会进行三角定位 会让我们足够接近 来吧
I'll triangulate. That will get us close enough. Come on.
回来的捷径
A shortcut back.
这可真有意思
This is pretty neat.
我们得走了
We have to go.
好 好的
Yep, all right.
哦 太好了
Oh, great.
我不懂怎么控制
I don't know any of these controls.
等等 I. V. A. N. ？
Wait. I.V.A.N.?
是我 船长？
Yes, Captain?
孩子 我很高兴见到你
Boy, am I glad to see you.
启动两分钟自毁程序
Initiate self-destruct sequence in two minutes.
好的 自毁倒计时开始
You got it. Self-destruct countdown initiated.
巴斯 你不想要这些很酷的技术吗？
Buzz, you don't want any of this cool technology?
只有你 伙计 来吧
Only you, buddy, come on.
-叛徒！-不
-Traitor! -No.
够了！
Enough!
只要告诉我晶体在哪里
Just tell me where the crystal is.
好吧 我们得保护我们的逃生船
Okay, we've gotta protect our escape ship.
那么 我们如何关闭这扇门呢？
So, how do we close this door?
我不知道
I don't know.
你说 "别担心 我们会把它封住的 "
What? You said, "don't worry we'll seal it off."
对 所以别担心 我们能办到的
Right, so don't worry. We will.
找到了
Here we go.
看见了吧?
Look, see?
怎么？
What?
喵喵喵
Meow meow.
现在信号更强了
The signal is tighter now.
他肯定在这边直走的方向
He has to be straight this way.
真是一个巨大的空间
That's a lot of space.
在一起 在一起
Keep it together. Keep it together.
不！
No!
我不明白 信号显示巴斯在50米外
I don't understand. The signal says Buzz is 50 meters away.
他在那边
He's over there.
你以为我们不一样吗 巴斯？
You think we're not the same, Buzz?
你已经是我了 只是你还不知道
You're already me, you just don't know it yet.
我永远不会成为你！
I'm never gonna be you!
如果你不成为我 那就不再会有你了
If you're not gonna be me you're not gonna be anyone.
人工重力解除
Artificial gravity disengaged.
该死
Blast.
不 不
No, no.
-嘿 你在做什么？-造个炸弹
-Hey, what are you doing? -Building a bomb.
好啊 你需要笔吗？
Nice, do you need a pen?
不 给
No. Here.
哦 谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
薄荷糖
Peppermint.
把包装纸给我
Give me the wrapper.
那么 你就可以用这些东西造一个炸弹了？
So, you can just build a bomb out of that stuff?
还差点东西 现在把口香糖给我
I worked with less. Now give me the gum.
等等 我还没吃够呢 味道还很足
Wait, I'm not done, there's still a lot of flavor left.
给我！
Come on!
瞧吧 当他们踩到它 就会爆炸
There. When they step on it it will blow up.
如果他们不踩呢？
What if they don't step on it?
我是说 反正我不会踩 你会吗？
I mean, I wouldn't step on that, would you?
那我们就得往上面扔重物
Then we need to drop something heavy on it.
-只要... -不！
-Just gonna... -No!
巴斯？
Buzz?
巴斯？ 巴斯！
Buzz!
阿丽莎？
Alisha?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
不 我一个人做不到 我需要帮助
No. I can't do it alone. I need help.
我不是我奶奶
I'm not my grandma.
依奇 我需要的不是你奶奶 我需要的是你
Izzy, I don't need your grandma, I need you.
索克斯 我们怎么去那里？
Sox, how do we get over there?
通过气闸
Through the airlock.
通过那里？
Through there?
外面什么都没有
There's nothing out there.
正是如此 没有东西挡你的路
Exactly. Nothing in your way.
可以直接过去
You just go straight across.
才不！
No!
让我把话说清楚 当这东西落在你的炸弹上时
Let me get this straight, when this falls on your bomb
-它一定会爆炸的 -是的
-it will definitely explode. -Yes.
-那就能封住门？-是的
-And that will seal the door? -Yes.
但是我们最好抓紧时间
But we better hurry.
我已经抓紧了
I am hurrying.
你怎么不抓紧呢?
Why don't you hurry?
加油啊
Come on.
好
Okay.
你行的 依奇
Come on, Izzy.
你做得到
You got this.
哦 伙计
Oh, man.
哦 不
Oh, no.
只要不往下看 也不往上看 这就是空间
Just don't look down, or up. It's all space.
它无处不在 在你周围
It's everywhere. All around you.
我很抱歉 我可能没帮上忙
I'm sorry, I'm probably not helping.
只管直走
Just go straight.
一旦你推开自己 就会朝那个方向过去
Once you push off that the direction you'll go.
但如果我错过了呢？
But what if I miss?
别错过
Don't miss.
什么？哦 不
What? Oh, no.
不 不！
No, no!
哇！
Whoa!
索克斯！
Sox!
谢谢你 依奇
Thank you, Izzy.
进不去
There is no way in.
也许我可以帮忙
Perhaps I could help.
你不能躲着我 巴斯
You can't hide for me, Buzz.
这就像在躲自己
It's like hiding from yourself.
我会找到你的
I'll always find you.
手动超控启动
Manual override activated.
-巴斯！-就现在！
-Buzz! -Now!
来吧 我们离开这里！
Come on, let's get outta here!
我们必须炸毁这艘飞船
We have to blow up the ship.
没有时间了 我们不可能成功的
There's no time. We'll never make it.
哦 是的 我们能
Oh, yes, we will.
自毁程序倒数10...
Self-destruct sequence complete in ten...
-... 9 8... -I.V.A.N. ？I.V.A.N.!
-...nine, eight... -I.V.A.N.? I.V.A.N.!
佐格.
Zurg.
达比 我们必须投降
Darby, we have to surrender.
不 我不会放弃的
No! I am not giving up.
是的 我也是 抓紧了
Yep, neither am I. Hold on.
-... 5 4... -我们走吧
-...five, four... -Let's go.
-... ...3 2... -大家都进来
-...three, two... -Everyone, get in.
...1
...one.
巴斯光年任务日志
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
我们已经摧毁了佐格飞船和佐格本人
We've destroyed the Zurg's ship and Zurg himself.
现在我只需要追上犰狳号 以便...
Now I just have to catch up to the Armadillo in order to--
你要去哪儿？
Going somewhere?
警告 引擎灾难性损坏
Warning, engine damage is catastrophic.
巴斯光年任务日志 我现在拥有了晶体
Buzz Lightyear mission log. I now have the crystal in my possession,
终于可以完成任务了
and can finally, at long last finish the mission.
我要回去重来 巴斯
I'm gonna go back and matter again, Buzz.
你呢？
And you?
你会像从没存在过
You will be like you have never here.
准备去死吧
Prepare to die.
今天不行 佐格
Not today, Zurg.
我们已经进入了这个星球的引力范围
We've entered the planet's gravitational pull.
我们会坠毁吗？
Are we gonna crash?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
巴斯！
Buzz!
我做不到
I can't do it.
巴斯 没关系的
Buzz, it's okay.
我们可以
We can.
你能保持飞船稳定吗？
Can you keep the ship steady?
是的 我想可以
Yeah. I think so.
好的 索克斯 把应急电池与飞行控制的电源接上
Okay, Sox, fuse the emergency battery the power of flight controls.
明白
Got it.
我需要一个副驾驶
I'll need a co-pilot.
好的 但我只在模拟器上做过这个
Okay, but I've only done this in the simulator.
好 那现在就要来真的了
Well, it's about to get real.
记住 向后拉动操纵杆--
Remember, pull back on the yoke--
-放松点 -是的 对不起 从现在开始 我会好好干
-Easy. -Yep. Sorry. Nice and easy from now on.
没用的！
It's not working!
我们速度太快了
We're going in too fast.
-I. V. A. N. -是的 船长？
-I.V.A.N. -Yes, Captain?
-我们太快了 -恭喜！
-We're going too fast. -Congratulations!
我们不要纸屑 我们要减速！
We don't need confetti, we need brakes!
哦 我知道了！
Oh, I know!
-反推装置！-在地板上
-The air brake! -On the floor.
达比！
Darby!
-它卡住了 -什么？
-It's stuck. -What?
盖子 它被卡住了
The cover, it's stuck.
我需要一把螺丝刀 或者一把剪子
I need a screwdriver, or a hair clipper
小锥子什么的
Some sort of a small wedge.
我有笔！
I've got the pen!
-巴斯！- 大家都还好吗？
-Buzz! - Is everyone okay?
-是的 -我想是的
-Yeah. -I think so.
是条子！大家快跑！
The cops! Everybody, run!
等等 这只是救援队
Wait. It's just the rescue team.
对 好的
Right. Okay.
你看起来是个正直的人 怎么会被关起来？
You seem like a decent citizen. What led to your incarceration?
我偷了艘飞船
I stole a ship.
我们中谁又没在绝望的时候...
Who among us hasn't stolen a ship in a moment of...
偷过什么飞船呢？
relative desperation?
我是个足智多谋的人 我的武器就是聪明才智
I'm a man of resources. My weapon is ingenuity.
我可以做任何事情！
I can do anything!
能别在我耳边大叫吗？
Can you not shout in my ear?
是的 对不起
Yep, sorry.
还好吗？
You're okay?
我上过了太空了
I was in space.
你奶奶会以此为傲
Your grandma would be proud.
她也会以你为傲
She'd be proud of you too.
她一直如此
She always was.
等等 你的晶体呢？
Wait. Where is your crystal?
没了
It's gone.
但你的任务...
But your mission...
你不是想回家吗
You wanted to go home.
你知道吗 这么久以来 第一次
You know, for the first time in a long time
我觉得我已经到家了
I feel like I am home.
佐格
Zurg.
小心！
Look out!
哇？
Whoa?
不许动！
Stop right now!
光年
Lightyear.
你盗窃了星际指挥部的财产 偷了实验飞船
You absconded with Star Command property, stolen experimental spacecraft
并违抗你指挥官的命令
and defied a direct order from your commander.
我应该关你的禁闭
I gotta throw you into stockade.
但我为你制定了别的计划
But I have other plans for you.
我们想让你建立一个新的太空游侠团队
We want you to start a new version of the Space Ranger Corps.
宇宙保护部
Universe Protection Division.
你将再次成为一名太空游侠 巴斯
You're gonna be a Space Ranger again, Buzz.
你可以从扎普巡逻队的精英中亲自挑选你的团队
You can hand-select your team from the very best of the Zap Patrol
并按照你的喜好训练他们
and train them to your liking.
Zap, zap!
好吧 你真好 先生
Well, that's very kind of you, sir.
但恐怕我不得不拒绝
But I'm afraid I'm going to have to decline.
我已经有了自己的团队
I already have my team.
这些新装备真牛X 臂部发射器 还有火箭翼
These new suits are amazing. Arm blaster, rocket wings.
都抵不过一只笔
It could use a pen though.
真不敢相信我被允许携带武器了 要是双枪就更好了
I can't believe I'm allowed to carry this. I wish I had two of them.
你现在的记录干干净净 又有自由了 又有装备了
You got a clean record. and you're free and armed.
还抱怨个什么？
How are you still complaining?
我是因为表现良好而被释放的 而不是因为态度好
I got off for good behavior, not good attitude.
你知道 我本来从不穿裤子
You know, I never wear pants,
但突然觉得不穿裤子很奇怪
but suddenly it feels weird to not be wearing pants.
不穿裤子看起来很奇怪吗？
Does it look weird without pants?
不 看起来很好
No, you look good.
我希望我可以把它拉下来
I wish I could pull that off.
瞧啊 奶奶 我成为了太空游侠
Look, Grandma, I'm a Space Ranger.
就像你一样
Just like you.
好了 队员们 我们在第四区的伽马象限发现了一个信号
All right, team, we've picked up a signal in the Gamma Quadrant of Sector 4.
我们不知道它是什么 但我们不会等待它来入侵我们的家园
We don't know what it is, but we're not gonna wait for it to invade our home.
收到 指挥官 不会让你失望的
Copy, Commander. You can count on us.
巴斯光年任务日志 星际日期4071年
Buzz Lightyear mission log. Star date 4071.
作为精英宇宙保护小组的成员
As members of the Elite Universe Protection Unit
作为太空游游侠团队的成员
of the Space Ranger Corps,
我们的任务是保护星系不受任何敌人入侵
we've been charged to protect the galaxy from the threat of invasion
任何星系联盟的死敌
from any sworn enemies of The Galaxy Alliance.
好了 各位 请确保你们都系好了安全带
Okay, everyone, make sure you're securely fastened.
-我们都准备好了吗？弹药？-没问题
-Do we have everything? Munitions? -Check.
-营养品呢？-我带了三明治
-Sustenance? -I brought sandwiches.
你不会因此吐一飞船？
And your tummy will be okay?
-都准备好了 -好的
-All set. -All right.
我有没有忘了什么？
Am I forgetting anything?
我想我们已经一切就绪
I think we're ready.
你好 我是你的内置声控导航仪
Hello, I am your internal voice-activated navigator.
很高兴你能回来 I. V. A. N.
Good to have you back, I.V.A.N.
光年船长 准备发射
Captain Lightyear, ready for launch.
-索克斯？-喵？
-Sox? -Meow?
I.V.A.N. 启动光速飞行
I.V.A.N., initiate hyper-launch.
当然可以
Certainly.
好了 太空游侠们 出发
All right, Space Rangers. Here we go.
飞向宇宙
To infinity
浩瀚无垠
and beyond.
01:35:50和01:43:37还有彩蛋
Keep tuned for TWO post credit scenes at 01:35:50 and 01:43:37. Cheers.
激光护盾
Laser shield.
如果你更喜欢一条风景优美的路线
Now, should you prefer a more scenic route
就往南走 经过亚溴酸盐沼泽
you'll want to head south past the bromite swamps,
令人叹为观止的景色 至少我听说是这样
a breathtaking sight, or so I am told.
但如果你赶时间 这将是你最近的路线
But if you are in a hurry, this would be your most direct route.
还有问题吗？
Any questions?
人呢？
Hello?